Remember who the enemy is.
The Hunger Games: Catching Fire is a adventure, action,
science fiction film directed by Francis Lawrence.
After surviving the Hunger Games, Katniss and Peeta struggle with the
consequences of their victory as unrest spreads across Panem.
Forced back into the spotlight, they become symbols of hope and resistance while the Capitol
prepares a new and deadly challenge that will change the future of the nation forever.
Katniss Everdeen, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Peeta Mellark, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Gale Hawthorne, played by Liam Hemsworth.
Haymitch Abernathy, played by Woody Harrelson.
Effie Trinket, played by Elizabeth Banks.
President Coriolanus Snow, played by Donald Sutherland.
The Hunger Games: Catching Fire is a 2013 American dystopian action film directed by Francis Lawrence from a
screenplay by Simon Beaufoy and Michael deBruyn, based on the 2009 novel Catching Fire by Suzanne Collins.
The sequel to The Hunger Games (2012), it is the second
installment in The Hunger Games film series.
The film stars Jennifer Lawrence, Josh Hutcherson, Liam Hemsworth, Woody Harrelson, Elizabeth Banks,
Lenny Kravitz, Philip Seymour Hoffman, Jeffrey Wright, Stanley Tucci, and Donald Sutherland.
In the film, Katniss Everdeen (Lawrence) and Peeta Mellark (Hutcherson) become targets of
the Capitol after their victory in the Games inspires uprisings in Panem.
Lionsgate announced a sequel film based on Collins' second Hunger Games novel in 2012, with Gary Ross initially set to return as
director; Ross was replaced with Lawrence that May, while deBruyn completed several rewrites to Beaufoy's screenplay.
The main cast was confirmed by September 2012 and principal
photography began later that month, lasting until March 2013.
Filming locations included Georgia, Hawaii, and New Jersey.
The Hunger Games: Catching Fire premiered at the Odeon Leicester Square in London on November
11, 2013, and was released in the United States on November 22, by Lionsgate.
It received critical acclaim, with praise for Lawrence's performance, action sequences, musical score, screenplay,
visual effects, emotional depth, and themes, with many considering it to be the best film in the series.
The film grossed $865 million, making it the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2013, the highest-grossing film featuring a female
lead since The Exorcist (1973), the highest-grossing Lionsgate film, and the highest grossing film of the series.
It also set the box office records for the biggest November opening weekend and
the biggest Thanksgiving period box-office total at the time.
Among its accolades, the film was nominated for the Broadcast Film Critics Association
Award for Best Action Film and a Saturn Award for Best Science Fiction Film.
For her performance, Lawrence was nominated for the Empire Award, Broadcast Film
Critics Association Award, and Saturn Award for Best Actress.
The soundtrack's lead single, "Atlas" by Coldplay, was nominated for the Grammy Award for Best
Song Written for Visual Media and for the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song.
The film was followed by its third and final installment in a two-part sequel: The Hunger Games:
Mockingjay – Part 1 in 2014 and The Hunger Games: Mockingjay - Part 2 in 2015.
The film explores themes of rebellion, based on novel or
book, propaganda, dystopia, uprising.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.